♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in red jump suit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ Then we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ When the movies begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts, ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call, let's go ♪
♪ Cambot, pan left ♪
♪ Gypsy, hi girls ♪
♪ Tom Servo, hi tall guy ♪
♪ Crow, I'm the wise cracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats & breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
its just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
♪ In the Blue Ridge
Mountains of the-- ♪
- Clay, Clay!
I think I was spotted
on my way down here.
- Did you wear your disguise?
- I was wearing my disguise,
but I'm just not
very good in heels.
- No one must know we're
down here doing this.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, it's time to call
Joel about the experiment.
Come in, Joely Poely,
pudding and pie.
- Hey, sirs, I'm ready for
this week's invention exchange.
Check this thing out.
I just made it.
It's the world's only
electric bagpipes, alright?
(bagpipes screeching)
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
Okay, and the robots
and I have worked up
a special cover version of Led
Zeppelin's "Whole Lotta Love"
You ready, guys?
- Ready.
- Two, three,
- Rock it!
♪ She's got a whole lotta love ♪
♪ What a whole lotta love ♪
♪ A really whole lotta love ♪
- I love it.
Look, Larry's
corneas are bleeding.
Well, it's time we sent you
our experimental
nugget this week, Joel.
Now, human underarm perspiration
is something that
happens to everyone
after they go through puberty,
which I assume
includes you, Joel.
(chuckles)
When's the last time
you saw a dog sweat?
Larry?
- Never!
- Exactly.
And why is that?
- Dogs don't sweat.
That's why.
- Exactly.
Because of the
dog's pineal gland.
Nature's own canine
antiperspirant.
Now you take a pineal
gland and you make a serum.
Get a dog, it doesn't
matter what kind of dog,
and you inject that serum
into a human subject.
In this case, Larry.
- Injections already?
- Now, let's see.
It's so hard to find
a spot I haven't hit.
Uh, what's this flower
and who's Roseanne?
- Oh, just stick it, will you?
- Sail on, silver bird.
- Oh!
- Now,
- Geez!
- Instantly the serum races
through the bloodstream
like a Porsche Targa 911,
commandeering each pore,
slamming it shut like the vault
at your favorite
savings and loan.
And checking the
wetness sensors,
we see that they are free
from wetness and/or odor.
(Larry panting)
Oh, yes, the antidote.
There you go, the antidote,
and here is your treat.
(Larry chomping)
- Oh brother!
- That was pathetic.
- Hey, no, I thought that
was really good, you guys.
You're doing really
well, and I think
that someday you'll be
ready for the Nobel Prize.
- Maybe for fiction.
- Hey, I noticed you moved.
You guys must've got kicked
out of Gizmonic Institute
for shooting us into
space like this, I bet.
- Oh, don't be ridiculous.
We moved.
- It's our grand reopening.
Welcome to Deep 13.
- Deep 13, wait a minute.
That's in the sub-basement
of Gizmonic Institute.
I had to clean up a
flubber spill once there.
It's incredibly radioactive.
- But it hasn't
affected our brain any.
- We like it here.
Now we're even closer
to the atomic pile.
And one day...
- Well, I suppose
it's time for you guys
to start experimenting
on us again.
- I'll tell you when it's
time to do the movie,
you squinty-eyed space chimp.
- Oh, uh, Clay?
- What?
- It is time.
- Oh, yeah, I knew--
- Nice insult, though.
- I knew that, thank you.
Well, it's a real stink burger
of a film this week, Joel.
It's called "The Crawling Eye".
- It's got a bad audio track.
It's in black and white.
And worst of all, it
stars Forrest Tucker.
- Hmm, good name, bad actor.
(laughs)
I'll put in the tape.
(men cackling)
- Movies time!
(doors clanging)
(metal creaking)
- [Tom] This must be
a Paramount Picture.
Pardon me.
- Yep.
- [Joel] It's a
beautiful mountain.
- Hey, Jimmy!
- [Jimmy] Hang on a minute.
Come see!
- [Echo] Hey, Jimmy!
- [Joel] Quit, quit Shouting!
- [Jimmy] I tell you it's foggy.
- [Joel] It's a mountain,
it's supposed to be cold.
- [Jimmy] Wait a minute.
Someone's coming.
- That's a bad Carey Grant
right there, isn't it?
- Who is it Jim?
The abominable snowman?
- [Jimmy] I tell you,
there's someone coming.
- Funny.
- Oh, what a good one.
- [Jimmy] Who is it?
- [Man] No, no!
(screaming)
- [Joel] Going down.
Lemme help you there.
- [Crow] Mountain
flossing really repels me.
- Alright, now, pick it up.
- Heave, ho.
- [Tom] Heave.
- Can you see him?
- Not yet, he's
just below the lip.
- [Joel] Aw, he got that
hat from Mike Nesmith.
- Here he is.
Jim.
No!
- Come on, come on!
(grunts)
You idiot, we nearly had him.
Why did you let him go?
- Didn't you see him?
- What are you talking about?
- His head.
It was torn off.
- [Tom] You say that
like it's a bad thing.
The Crawling Eye.
Starring...
- [Crow] It should
be the crawling me.
- [Joel] Oh, Forrest Tucker,
he was from "F Troop".
- [Crow] Hey, Joel,
how are you supposed
to read these titles?
- [Joel] Oh, well
Crow, it's simple,
you see the line up there?
- [Crow] Uh huh.
- [Joel] That's, see
there's one there, see.
- [Crow] Oh.
- [Joel] You follow the
line and it shows you
right what to look at.
- We are here.
- Yeah.
- [Joel] They quit
doing it 'cause people
started figuring it out.
- [Crow] Kinda like
titles with idiot clips.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Duncan Sutherland.
Duncan, what a
yo-yo. (chuckling)
- [Joel] Good one, Tom.
- [Tom] Thank you so much.
- [Joel] They're
the men responsible.
(dramatic music)
- [All] Directed by us.
- Tempean.
- The light at the end
of the credits.
Ah.
- [Tom] Let's see,
gemini, gemini,
you'll be attracted
to a crawling eye.
Leos figure prominently.
- Anne?
- Hm.
- Were you dreaming?
- Oh, I don't think so.
Why?
- You were talking
in your sleep.
- Did I give away any secrets?
- [Crow] Just that you're a man.
- [Sarah] Not really.
I didn't quite catch his
last name. (chuckles)
Would you like some tea?
- No, thank you.
- You sure you feel alright?
- [Tom] What a babe.
- I feel wonderful.
I wish everyone would stop
treating me like an invalid.
- [Joel] How about a wheelchair?
- Look, Anne,
there's a mountain.
- Ooh.
- Mm.
- [Tom] I am Mount Svengali.
You will do as I say.
(dramatic music)
Hey, my paper!
What the--
- [Crow] Hey, dibs, dibs.
Everything on my lap I get.
- What happened, did I faint?
- Now don't worry, it's alright.
- Is there anything I can do?
- [Joel] You're Sergeant
O'Rourke from "F Troop".
Oh, my name is Alan Brooks.
- Oh, well I'm Anne Pilgrim
and this is my sister Sarah.
- Hello.
- [Joel] Billy.
- How do you do?
There we are.
- [Joel] That paper's shot.
- I'm sorry about your
newspaper, Mr. Brooks.
- Oh, that's alright, I've
got the baseball scores.
There you are.
- It's just a prop anyway.
That'll bring the color back.
- [Tom] It's red
dye number seven.
- Looks like you
might do with one.
- No thanks.
You have far to go?
- Geneva.
- [Joel] Oh, it's a big
convention town, isn't it?
- [Man] Next Trullenburg.
- Trollenberg?
- [Tom] Yes, Trollenberg.
- Sarah, we're getting
off at Trollenberg.
- That's my stop.
- What's the matter, and
you know we have to go
on to Geneva.
- No, I really can't
go on any further today.
We can stop at the Hotel Europa.
- What's the Europa?
We've never been to this place.
How do you know about
the Hotel Europa?
- I don't know.
- Anne, what's got into you?
- We're getting off at
Trollenberg, please Sarah.
- [Tom] Don't argue with me.
Trollenberg, home
of the crawling eye.
All stops lead to
a bloody death.
- [Joel] It's Mr. Haney.
- Oh, hey folks, sorry matey.
Did you have a nice trip?
- Hey Klein, nice
to see you again.
Oh, I'd like you to meet
Miss Anne and Sarah Pilgrim.
- [Crow] They'll drink anything.
- He's the pride of
the Hotel Europa.
Wonder if you could help us out.
These young ladies have arrived
without any reservations
but perhaps you
could put 'em up.
- Yes, I guess it
would be alright.
- Good.
- Thank you very much.
- The car's outside.
- Very good of you to put
us up at such short notice.
- Well, this is not yet
our season, you understand.
- Oh I thought now woulda
been about your busiest time.
- Well normally yes, but--
- [Tom] We've been having
trouble with the crawling eye.
- Is Hans still working for ya?
- Yes, Hans is still working
for us abroad, thank you.
- Cigarette Sarah?
- No thank you.
- [Joel] Hey, look you guys.
They're being
followed by a movie.
- How 'bout you, Herr Klein?
- Thank you, I don't smoke.
- They shouldn't have
started the climb.
- What are you talking about?
- An accident.
Last week, 12,000 feet
up the South Cull.
Three English students,
one of them was killed.
- Was there an
accident, Mr. Klein?
- On the mountain, these
things sometimes happen.
- What else do you know
about the Trollenberg?
- Peasants are
leaving the mountain.
They say it's bad luck.
- The mountain people
are very simple.
They are superstitious.
Oh, all these
stories are nonsense.
- What stories?
- [Joel] Nonsense stories.
- Disappearing into the
mist and never seen again.
- [Crow] She is informed.
- [Tom] When is Switzerland,
visit Trollenberg.
- [Joel] It's
really picturesque.
(light spooky music)
- [Joel] What a
lovely mat painting.
- Hans.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Crow] (speaking
foreign language)
what's that supposed to mean?
- [Tom] It means the
babes are coming.
- [Crow] Oh!
- [Tom] There they are.
- Hello, you must be Mr. Brooks.
Klein told us you were coming.
I'm Truscott, Philip Truscott.
- How are you Mr. Truscott?
- Klein, you didn't tell us we
were expecting other guests.
- Oh, this is Miss Sarah
Pilgrim and Miss Anne Pilgrim.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
- [Crow] They'll drink anything.
- Sarah and Anne pilgrim.
I'm sure we've met before.
The name rings a bell.
- Does it?
Would you mind if we
went up to our rooms now?
- [Joel] These
aren't my clothes.
I don't look good
in stripes at all.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] She could
eat corn on the cob
through a picket fence.
- Observatory at the
foot of the mountain.
A cable car.
There's a small hut
the climbers use.
You can see it from
the observatory.
It's all there, just like..
- Just like what, Anne?
- Well just like...
Sarah, why did I
want to come here?
What is it about this place?
Why do I feel I've
seen it all before?
- Don't worry about it darling.
Lots of people get
a feeling like that.
Perhaps you read
about it in a book.
Or a picture in a travel folder.
You mustn't let it upset you.
- No I mustn't.
Yes, you're right, I've
probably read about it.
- [Tom] In the script.
(upbeat music)
- Hi.
- How are ya?
- Need a hand?
- No, I think I can manage.
- Lovely spot, this, isn't it?
- It certainly is.
- You've been here
before, haven't you?
- Yes, once, a
couple of years ago.
- Good climbing.
- So they tell me.
- Don't you climb?
- [Alan] Not if I can help it.
- [Tom] Must be
his overnight gun.
- [Philip] Come for holiday?
With Herr Klein?
- Yes, isn't it?
- [Crow] Oh, this old thing?
Saved my life once.
- Attractive, those
two girls, aren't they?
- Certainly are.
- Pilgrim.
Familiar name.
I swear to you I've seen
them before, somewhere.
On the palladium
about a month ago.
They're a mind reading act.
Funny they didn't say anything.
- Well, perhaps they
wanted some privacy.
- [Joel] Just like me.
- I'll buy you a drink later.
- All right, good.
- [Tom] He knows
how to take a hint.
- [Joel] He's kinda testy.
Give me 06468 will you?
(Crow squeaking)
- [Philip] Yeah, I want you
to check on someone for me.
(Crow squeaking)
Alan Brooks.
(Tom and Crow
speaking gibberish)
He's American, he's
about 40 I think.
- [Crow] Was he on F Troop?
- [Philip] Try New York
first, and then Los Angeles
and then Washington.
- [Crow] Alright.
- [Philip] Okay.
- [Crow] Gotta go now.
- [Philip] Right.
- [Man] Hello there,
you'll be Brooks.
- [Tom] If you want me to.
- I'm Dewhurst, this is Brett.
- [Crow] We're the hat brothers.
- How do you do?
Looks like you're
going for a climb.
- Yes, we're going
up to Trullenberg.
Gonna have a noggin
before we start.
Care to join us?
- Alright.
- What's it gonna be?
- Scotch please.
- [Dewhurst] Scotch
and a cool bandit.
- [Crow] Nothing like a
little drinking and climbing.
- Keep the cold out tonight.
- You gonna stay the night?
- No, there's a hut at the
foot of the South Cull.
We'll sleep there
tonight and attack
the mountain proper tomorrow.
- [Crow] Unless it
attacks us first.
- Hello Truscott.
- [Tom] Who's the tomato?
- [Dewhurst] You
must be Miss Pilgrim.
- Yes, that's right.
- Oh, this is Mr.
Dewhurst, Sarah.
And Mr.--
- Brett.
- How do you do?
- would you care for a drink?
I appear to be in the chair.
Which is bon voyage.
- Thank you, I'll
have a Campari.
- Truscott?
- Scotch, please.
- Campari and another
scotch, Hans, please.
- Sit down, Sarah.
- Your sister's here
with you isn't she?
Klein told us.
- Yes.
- Would she care to join us?
- No, not just now.
- Quite an occasion for me.
My first climb up a mountain.
- [Crow] Aren't you kinda fat
to be climbing a mountain?
- He's a big boy, he's
in the Alpine club.
- How'd you come to
take up mountaineering?
- Wonder if you could
come find some reason
for all these accidents.
I'm a geologist.
I know all about rock
formations, that sort of thing.
Well, here we are.
Cheers.
- To a good climb.
- Keep an eye on
your rope, English.
- [Tom] Huh?
- Why rope in particularly?
- I don't know.
- Two missing last week.
- [Tom] Chill out.
- Nasty business, very nasty.
- [Joel] Nasty, nasty.
- Some kids climbing
on the South Cull
and one of them fell.
- They shouldn't have been
climbing without a guide.
- [Tom] Or shoes.
- Wasn't roped up
correctly and the rope got
caught up around his neck.
- Strangle him?
- Worse than that.
- [Crow] Killed him.
- Tore his head off.
- Even worse.
- Then is strangled him.
- That isn't the half of it.
- [Crow] It was the fall
that killed him.
- What did the villagers say?
- It's not for me to--
- What do they say Hans?
- [Tom] That's what they
say, "It's not for me".
- The guides who found
him, also his friends.
They swear the rope
was around his waist.
You understand,
it was still tied.
- But how could it have...
- The villagers had something
to say about that, too.
Haven't they, Hans.
- [Joel] It was a trick knot.
- Excuse me.
(suspenseful music)
- What do the villagers
say, Truscott.
- [Crow] They say,
"It's not for me".
- They say it that
it happened before.
- [Tom] They all say that.
- As I said, they shouldn't
allow any inexperienced
climbers up the
Trullenberg without guides.
There are bound to be accidents.
- Yes, you watch your ruby.
- We oughta be
moving if we wanna
make the hut before nightfall.
- [Tom] We've got a
death scene to make.
- Oh, I'm going up
to the observatory.
I'll hitch a ride with
you in the cable car.
That is, unless you're
gonna climb the whole way.
- Climb the whole way?
Not if I can help it.
(dramatic music)
You see, there are
certain chemical changes
that take place inside rocks.
It's called a physical
alteration of its structure.
At times it can
become like chalk.
Break away in your hand.
- What do you think
of that Brett?
- Hm?
Oh, I don't think
it's like that.
A mountain's a mountain.
Some people can climb
it and some can't.
- [Tom] Some people can
speak dialog, some can't.
Those who can't shouldn't try.
I'm here out of sufferance.
- How long you think it'll
take you to reach the hut
from the observatory?
- I don't know.
- Oh, about three
and a half hours.
It's an easy climb.
- [Tom] That's good, I'm
wearing a sport coat.
(wind blowing)
- [Tom] Meanwhile,
at the observatory.
- Professor.
Professor.
- How many more times
do I have to tell you,
I am not to be interrupted.
- I'm sorry sir, but there's
someone outside to see you.
- I don't care,
tell him to go away.
- He says his name is Brooks.
- Tell him to--
- [Tom And Crow] Huh?
- Alan Brooks?
- Yes sir.
- Well bring him
in, bring him in.
No wait, wait.
I'll bring him in myself.
- [Crow] No wait, wait, you
get him, no, I'll get him,
uh, yeah, I'll get him.
I have to do
everything around here.
- Alan, nice see you Alan.
Ha-ha.
They all get a smack for
leaving you out here.
Come in, come in.
Oh, it's good of you
to come and see me,
and on you holidays, too.
I was lucky it
was in Europe, no?
You got my letter?
- Yes.
- Well you don't say very much.
What's the matter,
you're not pleased to see
your old friend?
- (speaking foreign
language) Herr Professor.
- And how are you, Alan?
Ha-ha, come in, come in, ha-ha.
- [Joel] What a goof.
- Well Alan, what do you think
of our little observatory?
- [Joel] Groovy pad.
- You know the
government gives me
as much money as I want.
(chuckling)
- [Joel] Very retro, needs
some more color though.
- I show you something.
- A television?
- Better than windows.
So look.
- [Tom] Look, the
all weather channel.
These are mountains you won't
see on any other station.
- You see, television
cameras on the roof.
We watch everywhere.
(chuckling)
You know, the government, the
government, they say to me,
"Professor, do you have to
have such expensive things?
"Window are much
cheaper". (chuckling)
And I say, "I have
to have", and I have.
- [Joel] Do you
think that's funny?
- Science humor.
- That is the only window.
And even for that, we
have perfection, look.
- [Crow] Now the windows
are even smaller.
But I can make 'em big again.
- [Joel] You could
just get roller blinds.
- That will stand
up to any avalanche.
(chuckling)
but that too was very expensive.
- [Tom] Ho, ho, ho, ho.
- Well, Alan, come
into my office, huh?
Well Alan, here we are.
Same old mess, huh?
- [Crow] But it's
an expensive mess.
- [Professor] Well,
you're looking very fit.
- I look the same as always.
Come on, quit your
stalling, professor.
You forget I know ya.
You said in your letter that
I should see you right away.
What's so urgent?
- How long you been here
in Trullenberg, Alan?
- Got here this morning,
came right up to see you.
- [Tom] So you haven't
tried the fish yet.
- You haven't heard
about the accidents then?
- Yes, I heard
about the students.
- Yeah, that was
one of them, but,
but there have been others.
Many others.
- Where people climb mountains
there are lots of accidents.
- That's true, and sometimes,
the bodies, they disappear.
But here, the search
parties go out,
and always they find nothing.
Now why is that?
- [Tom] They're not
good search parties?
- [Joel] But they're expensive.
- I don't know.
- And then there is the cloud.
- What cloud?
- Come on, Alan, you know
what I am talking about.
The cloud where there
should be no cloud.
- [Joel] Oh yeah,
oh yeah, that cloud.
- Where there are mountains,
there are always clouds.
- But this one remains static
on the side of the
Trullenberg, it's never moved.
- Let's go.
- Oh, right.
- Hey.
- It's a freak of nature.
- A radioactive freak of nature.
- Radioactive?
- Mm hm.
- Can we see it from here?
- Come, I'll show you.
(doors clanking and slamming)
- Okay, what did you guys
think of the movie so far?
- Well, I thought
there'd be more music.
You know, more of a
Julie Andrews quality.
- Julie Andrews quality?
Isn't that a
contradiction in terms?
- Now come on, Crow, what did
you think of the movie so far?
- Well, Joel, I can't
understand why everybody's
so upset about
losing their heads.
What's so bad about that?
I've seen Servo's head on
the workbench lots of times.
- Yeah it screws right
off at the pop top.
- Ew.
(popping)
(laughing)
- Well listen,
it's not like that.
It's really, human beings
are made completely
different you guys.
Once our head are
separated from our bodies,
that's pretty much the
end of the show for us.
It's just the way we're made.
- Can't you use your
back up copy and reboot?
- No, nope, nothing like that.
- Well then why do people
say that they're always like,
"I'd lose my head if
it wasn't screwed on"?
- Yeah, people often
say their heads
aren't in the right places.
- Yeah, and Joel, once I
heard the scientists talking
and they said you had
your head up your a--
- Well Crow, that was just
a figure of speech, alright?
- Figure of speech?
Now what's that
supposed to mean?
- Oh, like a body of
a paragraph perhaps?
- I think that's
a literary figure.
- Oh, maybe like Edna
St. Vincent Millay?
- Now there's a body.
- Now listen you guys.
I'm trying to teach
you something, alright?
- Joel, what about head games?
- And head trips.
- And how do you
explain head cheese?
- Well, head cheese, I
don't explain head cheese
but here are some people who do.
(upbeat music)
- [Tom] Joel, will you carry
me everywhere from now on?
- [Joel] Sure, I gotta put
wheels on you sometime.
- [Crow] Hey, look, it's
that painting we saw earlier.
- [Professor] Alan, come here.
- [Tom] Hey, wait for me.
Hey.
- [Crow] Keep up.
- Now you see, here's
a map of the area.
- [Joel] Admittedly,
it's not a very good map.
- [Alan] The Trullenberg.
- [Joel] That's Trullenberg.
- That is this camera
on top of the roof here.
Now you see at the moment,
nothing, no reaction, nothing.
But remember, here is the cloud.
I turn on the scanner.
Now watch when it
passes the cloud.
- [Joel] Where's the cloud?
Where's the cloud again?
- Now you see it's passed
the cloud, nothing.
Watch it go around again.
- [Joel] Where's the cloud?
Where is it?
- [Tom] It's a cloud
of baked beans I think.
- [Joel] Sounds
like it, right Tom?
- [Tom] Sure does.
- Well, what do
you think of that?
Now Alan, I ask you to
think back three years ago
to what happened in the Andes.
- But, but this
can't be the same.
- Why not?
We have accidents like before,
we have the cloud like before.
Why can't it be the same?
- Too many things missing.
- [Crow] Like a plot.
- A mental compulsion.
- What is it?
- The girl on the train.
She suddenly decided she had
to get off at Trullenberg.
She was booked for Geneva.
But she had to get
off at Trullenberg.
- And did she?
- Yes.
- [Tom] She had to.
- She's at the hotel.
- There's climbers
on the Trullenberg.
- Climbers?
I thought they were
all scared away.
Where are they?
- 16 degrees West of due North.
- [Joel] Hey, it's "F Troop".
(whistling)
- [Professor] Improve our field.
- [Tom] Two guys, hey.
- [Crow] Captain Parmenter.
- [Tom] Isn't he too fat
to be climbing a mountain.
- [Alan] From the hotel.
They came up with
me on the cable car.
- Well, they should
be alright as long
as they stick to
their present track.
- [Crow] And they keep
their heads on their necks.
- The cloud is well to
the west of their path.
Alan, will you do something
about what I've told you?
- The cloud?
Do what?
- Inform the authorities.
- Look, I'm on a holiday.
Besides you haven't told me
anything that can be proved.
- I've told you about the cloud,
I've told you about
the accidents.
What more do you want?
- Facts, proof.
- [Joel] Scotch.
- Something that'll look
real in black and white
on the committee's desk.
I don't know, I'm not gonna
stick my neck out again
like I did in the Andes.
- But why?
You were employed by
the United Nations.
It was all in the report.
- Look, by the time the
Andes' report was in
there wasn't anything
left in the area,
explained or otherwise.
They practically accuse me of
dreaming the whole thing up.
If I was to take a hand
here, I'd have to have
a list of documented facts
and they'd have to
be pretty conclusive.
- [Tom] Or I'd look
like a dork again.
- You're an important man.
Why don't you get
through the firm.
- Politics, I'm only
important if I say something
about cosmic rays.
I say anything else, they tell
me to mind my own business.
- [Tom] Why don't
they give him to study
that he can pronounce?
- Maybe you should
speak to Klein.
- Hotel proprietor?
- And he's also the
mayor of Trullenberg.
Perhaps he could help.
Anyway, he could supply
us of the accidents.
- [Crow] He might
be more interesting.
- Then perhaps you'll
do something yourself.
- Huh?
(wind blowing)
- [Joel] Meanwhile, back
at Daniel Boone's house.
- [Tom] Damn, I'm just too
fat to be climbing a mountain.
(chuckling)
- [Crow] What a nice place.
- [Joel] Gee,
there's only one bed.
Guess we'll have to flip for it.
- [Tom] He's too fat to flip.
- [Crow] Hm, let me see, I could
kill the fat guy with this.
No, too flimsy.
Yeah, this is it,
nice and hefty.
- You alright?
Oh, take your pack off, man.
You can't relax like that.
- [Tom] I'll call
Weight Watchers.
(phone ringing)
- Hello?
Yes, operator.
You have arrived?
- [Joel] Mm hm.
- Good, good.
A night's sleep
will rest your mind.
(Crow imitating caller)
Yes, alright.
- Okay.
- Goodbye.
- [Crow] Thanks a lot, bye.
- (speaking foreign language)
They have arrived at the hut.
You see, you have
nothing to worry about.
It is just unfortunate
that this year
we have had many
inexperienced climbers.
- And what about the
rumors in the village?
- Well, you know these
people professor.
They are superstitious.
They like to believe
in fairy stories.
Gentlemen, you
understand, officially,
there's nothing we can do.
- [Joel] Except sit
here and drink heavily.
- [Crow] Dear diary, once
again the fat guy got the bed.
- Until we come back tomorrow?
If we travel light.
- I must have a sack
for rock samples.
- Oh, I think we
can manage that.
You can take your sack.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Penny
for your thoughts.
Think we'll ever get married?
- Visibility's is not too good.
It'll clear.
- Fog, out here?
- [Tom] Oh, it's just a
painting, sorry, my mistake.
- Coming down form the peak.
- Will this do, Miss Pilgrim?
- Oh, this'll be fine.
Quite a collection
you have there.
Now would somebody
bring Anne in please?
- Oh, yes.
- Do we have to?
- Now, you'll see
that I make no signals
to Anne and say nothing.
So it's impossible for any
sort of code to be used.
(Joel clears throat repeatedly)
- The bank note?
(Joel grunts)
- It's a mango.
- 500 Francs.
- Mm hm, mm hm.
(clears throat)
there's a number on it.
- Mm hm, mm hm, mm hm.
- H-O-1
- mm mm, mm mm, mm mm.
- 1-8-8
- mm hm, mm hm.
- Well done.
(crowd murmuring)
- And who does it
belong to, young lady?
- [Joel] (coughing)
Perverts, robbers.
- Well done.
(crowd murmuring)
- Pretty good.
- well good, very done,
very good.
- A rounded sort of object.
(robots grunting)
about the size
of a tennis ball.
Made of glass.
I think it's used
as a paperweight.
There's a model inside it.
A mountain and a little
hut, and when you shake it,
there's a snowstorm.
- [Crow] When you shake
it, the heads come off.
- [Tom] Rose bud.
- No.
Mountain, hut, two
men in the hut.
- Anne.
- [Crow] The fat
one takes the bed.
- There's a fat
one, he's asleep.
- In the bed.
- But he's not the one,
the other one,
sitting at the table.
- [Tom] Dreaming, doubting.
- [Crow] Writing in his diary.
- [Anne] He's the one.
Getting up.
Coming towards the door.
- [Joel] Maybe
she's not psychic.
Maybe she's controlling him.
If she shuts up,
maybe he'll sit down.
- [Anne] He's opening it.
Coming out, up the slope.
Up the slope.
- [Joel] Flash, Mr. and Mrs.
America and all ships at sea.
This is a banner extra,
front page stuff.
Girl has vision.
- Paperweights.
Glass paperweights.
(dramatic music)
- Whoa!
Got her.
- Dudes, she's mine.
I'll get her arm.
- I'm picking her up
at her knees.
(phone ringing)
- [Dewhurst] Hello?
- Hello, Brett?
- [Dewhurst] Dewhurst
here, what do you want?
- Are you all right?
- [Dewhurst] Yes, why?
- Is Brett there?
- Of course he is.
He won't go wandering off
in the middle of the night.
- [Joel] Hm?
- [Dewhurst] Wait
a minute, hold on.
- [Joel] I'm fat, now
I'm fat and awake.
He keeps calling me,
thanks for calling, jerk.
- Dewhurst!
Dewhurst, is Brett
there, can you hear me?
Dewhurst, are you there?
Hello, hello?
- [Joel] Gonna have to
walk back over here.
- [Crow] Could you
order me a pizza?
- You're right, he's not here.
He must've just gone out.
I better go look for him.
- No, don't do that.
You'll be lost in five seconds.
Just sit tight where you are.
- I think I should go, there
may be something wrong.
- No, you're not to move.
Stay in the hut.
What's the weather like?
- Not very good.
A heavy cloud coming down.
- Well then stay where you are,
there'll be somebody listening
to the phone all night.
If Brett shows up
or if you need us,
ring us here, will ya?
- All right.
- Bye.
- [Crow] Well, let's see,
something to hold me over.
Eh, well, I can't eat that,
it'll just make me hungrier.
Maybe the blanket.
(wind blowing)
- Brett!
Brett! (echoing)
(door closes)
(man speaking foreign language)
- [Joel] It was a bizarre
dream and you were all there.
- Where am I, what happened?
- [Joel] Fanny Flag and
Groucho and Carl Sagan.
And it was a Dick
Cavett PBS special.
- Well, we need something
to relax your sister.
A sedative perhaps, do
you have such a thing?
- I may have some
sleeping pills in my room.
Shall I see if I can find them?
- Oh, please, thank you.
(door opens and closes)
- Sarah, may I speak with
you for a minute please?
- Alright.
(squeaking)
I shan't be a minute.
- [Joel] What' that noise.
- [Tom] I think
somebody's sharpening
a pencil or something.
- [Crow] I think it's
the electric blanket.
(squeaking static)
- Now, Miss Sarah, I don't
want you to upset yourself.
- Are these any good?
- [Joel] He prescribed
those for Elvis.
- Yes, it's fine.
Now you give her two of these,
then come downstairs,
please Sarah.
- Alright.
- [Crow] Is it my breath?
(upbeat music)
(phone ringing)
- Hello?
- [Tom] My pizza ready?
Been over a half hour.
It's foggy as hell outside,
you know I can't see far.
Perishing cold, too.
Yes.
Hold on a minute.
There's someone
outside, hang on.
- [Joel] Maybe it's
the neighbor kids.
- [Crow] Could be the pizza man.
- [Tom] Hey, get
outta my flowers.
- [Crow] It's the
stealth pizza man.
- Brett, Brett is that you?
(dramatic music)
False alarm, I guess.
Hang on a minute, I'm
just gonna close the door.
(screams)
- [Joel] It's the noid.
- [Tom] Do we ever get
to see the monster, Joel?
- [Joel] I think they're sick.
- Dewhurst, hello, hello.
Dewhurst, are you there?
(screaming)
- [Crow] Anchovies.
- Well?
- [Crow] He said anchovies.
- The phone's gone dead.
(phone ringing)
- [Tom] That one hasn't.
- Hello?
Yeah, speaking.
Yes.
- [Tom] It's Harpo.
- I see.
- [Joel] Hm?
- Alright, alright.
- [Joel] He said anchovies.
- It was the observatory.
The cloud has moved
away from the hut.
Back out to Trullenberg.
- [Joel And Robots]
Hey, nice real change.
- We must get back Herr Horden.
- Jawohl.
- [Crow] You think this
outfit is too busy?
(speaking foreign language)
- Yah.
- We better start now,
it will be light soon.
- I thought the
locals were afraid
of going up that mountain.
- They are afraid.
There's an unwritten law here.
A time like this, they
go up no matter what.
- [Joel] Even without pants.
- I have called a charter plane,
but it will not
be up til morning.
We will be well on
our way by then.
Ready?
- All right, Herr Klein.
- [Tom] Should I have my glasses
on or off for this climb?
- Look after yourself Alan.
- Don't worry, I'll
stop by the observatory
on the way down.
- Good.
Be careful everybody.
- [Crow] Don't lose you heads.
- [Tom] These four brave men,
(screaming)
three brave men.
uh, two brave men,
soon to go down in
the annals of history.
- [Joel] Look at that staircase.
Would you look at
that staircase?
- [Crow] Wow, what a staircase.
- [Joel] Man, what a staircase,
boy I'm getting winded.
How about you, Forrest?
- [Tom] Oh, yeah.
- [Crow] Hey, quick side cast.
- [Tom] Got enough left
for this staircase.
Whoa.
- [Joel] Watch your step.
- [Crow] Why did they
bring so much licorice?
(Anne groaning)
- [Crow] Hey, she's chasing
rabbits in her sleep.
- Here they come.
- Professor.
- [Crow] Thumper, Fluffy, Bugs.
- [Tom] Rico, Young blood.
- They're climbing the ledge.
They'll be here soon.
And they'll be at the hut.
Keep them away.
Keep them away from the hut.
Away from the hut,
away from the hut.
- [Tom] And Starskey.
- [Crow] Hut, hut,
hut one, hut two.
(dramatic music)
Poor cooky kid.
- [Joel] Maybe she
shouldn't sleep so much.
- Professor, what's the matter?
Why does she behave like this?
- [Joel] She's a method actor.
- Well, it's like
a radio receiver.
You see, now your
sister's mind is capable
of receiving signals
sent out by other minds.
But yours, for example,
- [Tom] Let's start
with a simple test.
Can you tell where
I'm looking right now?
- There is a stronger signal,
I think, a stronger mind.
She's channeling the wavelength.
- [Crow] Is she AM or FM?
- And who is it?
- Well, we shall know
more about that, I think,
when they reach the hut.
In the meantime, I
plea with you again.
Get your sister out of
here before it is too late.
- Too late for what?
- [Crow] Last call, take out?
Too late for heroes?
Tell me!
- Well, it's time I was getting
back to the observatory.
- Too late for what, professor?
- [Crow] Last call?
Tell me, you're
keeping this from me.
- When they reach the hut,
then we will know
for sure, I think.
- [Joel] Ah.
(knocking on door)
- Door is locked from the
inside, they must be in there.
Mr. Brett, Dewhurst!
- I've looked in
through the window,
the place seems deserted.
- [Crow] Hey, a
doorknob, can I keep it?
- [Alan] Philip, come here.
- [Joel] Look out, ow.
- [Crow] Ow.
- These blankets, frozen stiff.
- [Joel] Must have slept with
his hand in lukewarm water.
- The door was
barred on the inside.
- Yes.
- Brooks!
- [Crow] Pants, with
the legs still in 'em.
- [Tom] Those are the best kind.
- [Joel] Careful not
to pull too hard,
his head might be
caught on something.
(speaking foreign language)
- Oh, yuck.
- He's huge.
- His head has been torn off.
- [Crow] Ripped off.
- Anne, we're
leaving here today.
- No Sarah.
- You fainted, Anne.
Look, after last night, surely--
- I just want to stay
here, that's all.
- [Joel] We haven't
tried the fish yet.
- Anne, I really mean this.
We're leaving Trullenberg today.
Alright?
- [Crow] You're
thinking of a color.
There's someone in
the room named Bob.
(chuckling)
Two super powers
will unite to fight a third.
- [Tom] Stop it.
- [Crow] Two brothers
will reach the senate.
One will become president
and both will die.
- [Joel] Shh, hush.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] Can I have that toast?
Are you gonna eat that toast?
- [Tom] The mad
painting is calling you.
Go to the window.
- [Joel] Go to the closet.
Unpack your clothes.
Open your suitcase, take
out a foundation garment.
Cut to another scene.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Joel] You guys
take the torso.
- Oh, okay.
- I'm getting outta here.
- For us, it's an
experienced climb.
We can only assume
that he's hurt.
They all have
their search orders
and the charter plane
should be here any minute.
(speaking foreign language)
(upbeat music)
- He's not gonna like this.
- And I'm not gonna
tell him, you tell him.
- Well, maybe he won't notice.
- Oh, yeah, right.
Hey, Cambot, can you speed
this up a little bit?
- Uh oh.
- Oh, he's here, oh.
- Joel, I don't want to be
teacher's pet or anything
but Gypsy uncoiled
herself again.
- Yeah she did, Cambot,
could you widen it out
so everybody can see this?
Gypsy, I know you're
in here, quit hiding!
You clown, get out here.
Oh, let's do that
thing we did, okay?
- Alright.
- It's too bad Gypsy's
not here, huh, Crow and Servo?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it's too bad
she's gonna miss out
on those piping hot ram chips.
- Mm.
- Ram chips?
- Oh, alright, I knew you
were around here somewhere.
Listen, you know you're
not supposed to come out
without using the
service portal.
Now look, I wanna show you this.
(Gypsy exclaiming)
See this big mess
you got all over the place?
Hey, this is how you look, okay?
Now otherwise, we're gonna
have exo service spinal bundle
all over the place.
- What?
- The black stuff.
- Oh, hey Joel.
- What's that?
- I got an itch.
- Oh wonderful.
- Oh terrific.
- She's got an itch.
Okay.
- Happy day.
- Okay, where is it, Gypsy?
- Vertebrae 6805 to 7219.
- Vertebrae 6905 through
7018, okay you guys,
start scratching.
Where's my rake
- Whoa!
- when you need it?
- Oh I hate it when she
gets diode rash.
(Gypsy moaning)
- Me too.
- Tom Servo, I think
you're scratching
on the solar collector cable.
- Oh, great.
- So am I.
Wait a minute, now.
- Why am I doing this?
I hate being the end man.
I scratch here and it
takes her six hours
to feel it in her head.
- I know what you mean.
- Joel?
- Yeah?
- I don't wanna ask
a stupid question,
but why'd you make her so big?
- Well you know how,
it's kinda like when you
start connecting
paper clips together,
you get hooked on it.
It's kinda like that.
- Oh my.
- What's that, Tom?
- Joel, do you remember when
we were speculating on her sex?
- Yeah.
- Well, I think I may have
narrowed it down here.
- Oh yeah?
- Oh, oh, oh, check that,
sorry, false alarm.
- Oh, wait a minute,
here's the, I think
I found the problem.
She's jammed in here
behind the door.
- Hey don't open
that door, McGee.
(whooshing)
- It happens every time.
We got movie-cide.
- Whoa!
(whirring)
(doors clanking)
- [Tom] I feel safe
in your arms, Joel.
(plane engine purring)
- Plane to party,
plane to party,
are you receiving me?
- [Joel] Party here, pick
up some ice and some cubes.
- Receiving you loud and clear.
- [Joel] Get some paper cups.
- [Pilot] What is your position?
- Our position, map
reference, 265843, over.
- [Joel] Can't miss it,
Dave's van's parked
right out in front.
(plane engine humming)
Vroom.
- Roger party, I
can see you now.
I shall fly north
for five miles.
- [Crow] For no apparent reason.
- Then west for five
miles, then south.
- [Tom] He'll be back
in the exact same spot.
- Roger, plane.
- [Tom] What the?
- [Crow] She didn't
make her bed again.
- [Tom] She's,
she's a nightgown.
- [Crow] She's not in there.
- [Joel] She's been
digging through my stuff.
- [Tom] Let's see, she
went to the closet,
she took my stuff, then she
must have gone to the window.
- [Crow] I didn't
know they had cable.
♪ The hills are alive
and it's getting scary ♪
♪ That cloud over there
wasn't there before ♪
- Hello?
- [Tom] Hello.
- I want to speak
to the observatory.
Professor Crevett.
(light music)
- [Tom] De plane, de plane.
- [Joel] Don't crash,
don't crash, don't crash.
If I concentrate, I won't crash.
- [Crow] Let's see, let's
find a flat spot here.
- [Joel] Whoa, here's the party.
- Hello party, this is
plane, I have spotted him.
I have spotted him.
He's approximately
half a mile due north
of your position,
about the north face.
- Roger plane.
- [Crow] Big part for him.
Look out for the
mountain. (imitates crash)
(light music)
- [Tom] Hi, I'm the curator
of the mat painting.
- My name's Wilde,
Professor Crevett said
to bring you to the observatory.
- But I'm not going
to the observatory.
- Well, there's nowhere
else to go out here.
It's only a couple
of hundred yards.
- I'm to go up the mountain.
- I don't think
so, Miss Pilgrim.
I think you ought to wait
a while at the observatory.
- [Joel] What color is
the sky in your world?
(whistling)
- [Tom] Just about,
almost, almost (grunting).
(speaking foreign language)
- [Joel] What?
- [Tom] He said,
here's a bloody bag.
Better have a look-see.
- Herr Brett! (echoing)
- [Joel] Echo!
- [Crow] Needs a shave.
- [Tom] What?
Pudding?
- [Joel] Maybe it's
somebody's lunch.
- Hey, (speaking
foreign language).
- [Tom] Coming see here schnell?
- [Crow] Alright, 'salright.
- [Tom] They found Hoffa.
You've looked in my bag!
- [Crow] Hey, buddy, it won't
get better if you pick at it.
- [Joel] Yeah, your
friend, I got a bone
to pick with you too.
- [Tom] I suppose you
wanna look in my bag too!
- [Joel] And it's yours.
- [Crow] That's gotta hurt.
(speaking foreign language)
(machine whirring)
- How 'bout that?
- Negative.
- Hugo?
- Bring it over 30 degrees.
(machine whirring)
- Negative.
- [Joel] Everybody's
so negative.
- Try the other circuit.
Oh, wait.
Switch it back to the first
circuit and reverse the scan.
- [Tom] This'll never
replace Nintendo.
- [Crow] Now's my
chance to beat it.
- [Tom] I hope I don't
run into Forrest Tucker.
Huh?
- Oh, hello Anne.
What are you doing up here?
- [Crow] Uh, nothing.
- [Joel] Probably waiting
for the commercial.
- Go, go where?
- To Trullenberg,
I must go, now.
- [Professor] Don't
let that girl go.
- Don't worry.
Come along now.
- Oh, good, Alan I
want to speak with you.
- Yeah, I got news for you too.
When does the next cable
car go down the mountain?
- It shouldn't be long, sir.
- Good I, I want you
to take Anne down,
don't let her outta your sight.
Anne, I want you
to go with Hans.
- [Joel] He's a warm
and wonderful man,
you will be very happy.
- [Tom] Groping Hans.
- [Crow] Hey everybody,
I got a girl.
They make a lovely
couple don't they?
- Well, I've been to the hut.
- And?
- Dewhurst is dead,
Brett's missing.
- Oy, not that I'm
surprised, mind you.
The cloud has
started moving again.
- What cloud?
- [Tom] Bozo the cloud.
- I don't think you'd
understand, Philip.
- [Crow] You're much too stupid.
- Like that time in the Andes?
- Hm?
- Doh.
- How'd you know about that?
- [Joel] Oh, I get around.
- Alright, I'm a newspaper man,
it's my job to know
about these things.
(groaning)
- I see.
- I chased that story
when we got a wind
of your report, Alan.
When I got there,
it was too late.
Looks as if I'm gonna be
more fortunate this
time, doesn't it?
- Yeah, fine, fine,
that's just what we need.
You haven't answered
my question, Professor.
- What question?
- Is this the same
as it was then?
- [Crow] Well, that was
then and this is now.
- So what happens now?
- [Joel] This.
- The United Nations
have a special team
for investigating phenomena.
Might call 'em in.
- [Tom] They also double
as our softball team.
- The theory that you
put forward last time
still hold, Professor?
- What theory?
- Visitors from outer space,
that was it, wasn't it?
- Well, what else?
- Well, what are they?
What do they want?
- Look, Philip,
there are many galaxies
- The fish.
- besides ours.
Now, who knows what
is happening millions
of miles out in space.
- Sagan knows.
- Perhaps the world
that these creatures
inhabit is coming to an end.
Perhaps they need to find
somewhere else to live.
- Well why pick on us?
- We don't know it's just us.
Maybe it's also on Mars,
Jupiter, Venus, who can tell.
- Do you go along with this?
- Until somebody comes up
with a better theory, yes.
- Or a sitcom.
- Yes, I do.
- Alright, alright,
while we're theorizing,
why, do you think,
do they always happen
to land on the top of mountains?
First the Andes, and
now the Trullenberg.
- Well, it's the
atmosphere, I think.
You see, it gets
much thinner high up.
Perhaps these
creatures need that.
The cloud would seem
to indicate it too.
Creating their own atmosphere.
- Well if they can only exist
on the top of mountains,
they are hardly likely to
inherit the earth, are they?
- You see, anyone can get
used to anything in time.
- [Tom] Like I, you.
- Now this movement
we have recorded here,
each time lower
down the mountain.
The climatization flex.
- What next, Professor?
- The next move
is up to you Alan.
You must inform the authorities.
- [Crow] Or the authorities.
- Have you seen the professor?
- He's in the office
with Alan Brooks,
they're telephoning Zurich.
- Any sign of Mr. Brett yet?
- Well the plane spotted
someone he thought was human,
two of the searchers
went to meet him.
The others are betting
they'll see nothing.
- Well if they won the bet,
they oughta be back by now.
- Where's your sister?
- She's in her room.
- Good.
- You think she's safe
from our friends up there?
- Well, I don't think they'll
try the same thing again.
The trouble is,
what will they try?
(whistling)
(imitating western music)
- [Crow] Wow, he looks
dead on his feet.
- A bit tired,
otherwise alright.
- Where have you been?
We've had search
parties out for you.
- I was lost.
- [Tom] In a fog, if you will.
- Dewhurst get back alright?
- When did you see him last?
- Dewhurst?
- Yes.
- Last night, I saw him.
- At the hut?
- Yes at the hut.
It's a bit hot in here.
Pour me a drink, Klein.
- Have one on me.
- [Sarah] Let me help you.
- Sorry.
Thank you.
- [Crow] He can't
handle his liquor.
- How's your sister,
Miss Pilgrim?
- She's all right now.
- What do they think?
- She's in--
- Here,
have a cigarette.
- [Tom] Great, we saw how
well he did with the booze.
Now let's give him
something that's lit.
429 matches exactly,
exactly 429.
- [Joel] That's a good
impression, Servo.
- [Tom] I'm an excellent driver.
(Joel chuckling)
- [Crow] He's gonna
light his nose, look out.
- [Joel] What are
they gonna do next,
have him drive a
fork lift, you guys?
Jeez.
Glutton for punishing
others. (chuckling)
- [Crow] Let's get
the dog drunk next.
(chuckling)
- It's too scary up
there on your own.
- Were you all on your own?
- After I lost Dewhurst--
- I'm sorry to be a
nuisance, but may I--
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Then she walked in.
Ooh, owie.
- He's kinda pig headed.
- [Crow] That smarts.
- Look at his head.
- [Crow] At least he's got one.
- But, there's no blood.
- [Tom] He's wearing
Mr. Spock's jammies.
- [Joel] Dig a little deeper.
- [Tom] Yeah, that's a good
idea, solder him back together.
- There, that should
take care of him
until the morning, I think.
- Good.
- [Crow] He should be up and
spilling liquor in no time.
- Dr. Becker can
have a look at him.
- Do we tell the others
what he was trying to do?
- I don't know.
- Looks great.
- [Crow] Let's lock him in here.
- I could use a drink.
- [Joel] So what else is new?
- [Joel] I think we
all could use a drink.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Who put this
zipper in my head?
Wow, what a party,
I'm dead tired.
A little thirsty
though, I need a drink.
Maybe some formaldehyde.
Hope they serve the dead here.
- [Joel] Looks like Popeye.
(Tom imitating Popeye's laugh)
- [Tom] Oh, somebody's coming
down the hallways, geh.
- [Joel] Doesn't look
like anybody's in there.
Uh oh, I'll see about
that. (groaning)
- [Tom] Eh, I think I'll reach
through and get hims, geh.
- [Joel] Oh, hey,
Popeye, ooh, oh.
♪ I'm Popeye the sailor man ♪
♪ I've got a guy's
head in my hand ♪
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] This legal
submission hold.
- [Crow] Sounds like a bad
Popeye impression to me.
(grunting)
- [Joel] I think you
proved your point.
- [Tom] Dropped him
like a bad habit.
- [Crow] He's just
misunderstood.
- [Tom] Most dead people are.
- [Joel] He'll make
an excellent puppet.
There's Ward Cleaver.
- [Crow] What do ya think
he's gonna do with that?
(suspenseful music)
Mind if I cut in?
- [Tom] Here's Johnny.
Wendy, I'm home.
Pretty lady?
- Alan.
- [Crow] Norman, I told you
not to bother the guests.
- Alan, oh Alan.
- [Tom] Oh, my.
- Alan, Alan, wake up please.
Alan please, Alan, come quickly.
(screaming)
(gun fires)
- [Tom] And that's for
killing the fat guy.
- [Crow] Whoa, carries
a pistol in his pajamas.
- [Joel] What do you think
that pocket's for, Kleenex?
- Look at this.
- What?
- Hans, bring the light closer.
- [Tom] Lower, lower.
- Lower.
- Lower!
- Put it on the floor.
- Lower.
- Even lower.
- See the way the flesh
reflects the light?
- [Joel] Pretty.
- Almost as though
it's crystallized.
Like meat that's
been deep frozen.
- I still don't
understand how such a--
(yelping)
- [Crow] Wow, unfortunate skin.
(gasping and gagging)
- [Joel] Did we
have to see that?
- Alan, the observatory's
not been on.
That cloud is moving again.
- [Tom] Well, we haven't
seen the monster yet.
It's good to see something.
- [Joel] It's coming.
- You're wasting your
time, that phone is dead.
The wires have been cut.
We gotta get up to
the observatory.
- But we must--
- You heard what
the professor said,
that place is built like a fort.
If we're gonna have any direct
contact with these things
at least we'll have some
kind of chance up there.
- It's insane, we should try
to get out to the valley.
- The road is blocked, the
cloud stretches right across it.
- [Joel] Now go out and
do something irrational.
- Yes, yes, you go out on the
next cable car with the girls.
- [Tom] Hey, dudes.
- You got everyone?
- [Man] Not everyone,
we've got 12 left.
One car's already gone
up, and the other one
will be down in 10 minutes.
(car revving)
- Who is that?
- Hey.
- Hans.
- [Tom] Hey Hans, get some ice.
(car revving)
Poor fool.
- Alright everybody, let's
get up to the cable car
as quickly as we can.
We haven't got very much time.
- [Crow] Oh really?
I thought we'd just hang
around for an hour or two.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Uh oh.
- What about Hans?
- [Crow] I bet they'll
be back for that.
- He's driving through
the cloud.
- [Joel] I didn't
know they got cable.
- [Crow] Both channels.
- [Tom] If we only had a bomb.
A small rubber bomb,
then we'd be fine.
- [Crow] Wait, I think I
know where we can find one.
- Professor, are you sure
we're doing the right thing
coming up to the observatory?
- (speaking foreign
language) I don't know.
What I do know is, it's wrong
to stay down in the village.
Up there, we have
some chance at least.
- Professor, look,
on the lower slopes.
The cloud, it's moving faster.
- I hope they see it down there.
- The operator says it
is five minutes now.
- Good.
- Alan.
The cloud's moving
pretty fast now.
(dramatic music)
- Please folks, I'd
like you all to be ready
to load in the car as
soon as it gets down.
We haven't got a
second to spare.
- [Tom] Why don't you just
spew out more obvious facts?
- At least we'd know what
we we're dealing with.
- Well, we'll know soon enough.
- [Crow] Wow, is that
tastelessly done.
It's such a mish-mash of styles.
- [Joel] Kinda
garish all around.
- [Crow] Who
decorated this joint?
- [Tom] Someone with a
really big butt sat there.
Is that the crawling eye, Joel?
- [Joel] No, that's
the little ball.
See now, this is where
your weatherizing
would really pay off.
They're probably
losing up to 70%
of their heat out that door.
- Seems to have
stopped at the hotel.
- Yeah, well, as long as it
stays there, we're alright.
At least that cloud lets
us see where it moves.
Let's get aboard as
quickly as possible please.
That's it, there you are.
Please mam, please.
- My kid, where's my kid?
- Of course, the child.
(dramatic music)
- If that cloud starts to move
this was before I get back,
take the car up,
do you understand?
- What about you?
- Do as you're told.
- Whoa!
- Holy, what the?
- Look at that!
- Ah, jeez.
- [Tom] I'm on the
edge of my seat.
- [Joel] He thinks that
ball's one of his pupils.
- [Tom] (laughing) Stop
it, you're killing me.
Ooh, look at that
milky discharge.
I think he has conjunctivitis.
(child crying)
- [Joel] Now look here, you.
Give you a trim.
- [Crow] Hey wait,
what about the ball?
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] Hey.
- Get in the cable car.
That's it.
- [Tom] Tickets, everyone?
- [Joel] I don't need one.
- [Tom] And Forrest Tucker.
- [Tom] Oh look, it fell
off its fabric softener box.
- [Crow] Now they gotta
go back for the bear.
- [Joel] Oh, we
better get outta here.
- I'm outta here.
- Carry me, honey.
- That was a close shave.
- We're not through yet.
(doors clanking and slamming)
(whirring)
- Oh, Joel, it
was so horrifying.
- Yeah, really, you think so?
- So ugly, so hideous.
- Oh yeah, that was
some eye, wasn't it?
- No, not the eye, we're
talking about Forrest Tucker.
- Oh yeah, all that
vitalis, those prop glasses,
and those heavy,
dramatic pauses.
I'm drained.
- No, you guys,
no, you got it wrong, you see.
The eye is what's horrible about
this movie, think about it.
Otherwise it woulda been called
The Crawling Forrest Tucker.
- I guess.
Joel, what's so scary
about a big eye anyway?
- Oh, I see, well that's
another human being thing.
You know, any time
we're confronted
with some appendage of
ours that's disconnected
and free-roaming, rogue, you
know, genetically bloated
to 10 times its normal size,
we're automatically scared.
- Especially if
they run in packs.
- Oh-ho, I know what you mean.
Once I got hassled by a pack
of really tough
pituitary glands.
And you know how
immature they can be.
- I still don't see
why it's so scary.
You can just walk up to
it and throw salt at it.
- Or just a squeeze
of lemon juice.
- Right, I know, it's
kind of a plot hole,
but let's kinda look it over.
You see these, okay,
these giant eyes
come from a world that's
designed for 'em, you know.
It's completely compatible,
like their highways
are made outta Nerf
and they don't have
to take shop classes.
- And they only
use baby shampoo?
- Right, right
exactly, so anyway.
They come down from this
planet and they decide
to land on a mountain peak.
- Which is really stupid,
'cause as we all know,
a giant sharp point is the
giant eye's natural enemy.
- Bingo, so anyway.
They come down and they fouled
up their atmosphere somehow,
I don't know, it's hay
fever season or something,
and they figure they'd
come down to Earth.
We'll have our first
frost already done with
so they come down and
they have no concept
of anything at all like
wearing safety glasses
or protective
eyewear of any kind.
- Joel, I think we've
already spent more time
examining this plot than
the writers ever did.
- Now here's something
you'll really like.
(upbeat music)
- [Joel] This is the last time.
- [Tom] Put me down.
As a fog emerges
over Trullenberg,
our young group escapes.
- [Joel] Looks like
everything's free and clear now.
Nothing to do but
to get up the rope.
- [Tom] Sit back and relax.
- [Tom And Joel] Enjoy the ride.
- [Tom] Uh oh, maybe
we spoke too soon.
- [Joel] Oh, now they're
gonna have to wait all day
for that cable guy to show up.
- This contraption operate
in the extreme cold?
- We've worked the
cable car at 30 below.
- Colder than that?
- [Crow] Colder than a winch.
- [Joel] Tell scary stories.
- [Tom] Oh my.
- The cable!
It will snap.
- [Tom] Am I gonna have
time to change my pants
when we get there?
- [Joel] Oh funny, good one.
Tell 'em all about the
giant eye, Forrest.
- All right quick,
everybody out.
That's it.
- We're keeping the
villagers out here, sir.
The shop is safe and they
won't get in the way.
- Are the radios still working?
- We checked about
15 minutes ago, sir.
- Oh, Alan, come here.
Alan we are in big trouble.
- Well what now?
- The cloud is splitting up.
- Splitting up?
- There are four of them
now and all moving this way.
- [Crow] Four eyes.
- How long before they get here?
- An hour maybe.
- Then we've got just
an hour to decide
what we're gonna do.
You better check
that radio again.
- You're going to
signal the authorities?
- To tell them what?
What are used
against these things?
- High explosives?
- Bombs?
By the time the plane get here,
those things will
be all over us.
How do they drop
their bombs then?
- The third is still
working okay, sir.
- Good, lemme see
that thing again.
- Here's someone knocking at
the outside door, Herr Wilde.
- [Joel] It's Bob Hope.
- [Tom] Hey there,
join me this week
with Brooke Shields
and Erik Estrada.
- [Joel] Maybe he's doing
a walk-on in this movie.
- [Tom] Is that a
good Bob Hope joke?
- If we don't make up
our minds pretty soon,
they'll be made up for us.
- [Joel] What does
he mean by that?
- What's the matter?
What happened?
- [Tom] He looks plastered.
- It went straight
across the road.
I turned the car and came back.
- You alright?
- [Crow] Couldn't get
it out of first, huh?
- I'm all right, thank you.
It is so hot in here.
- [Crow] Uh oh.
- Stay here with
the others, Hans.
You'll be alright soon.
- [Joel] And don't
breathe on anybody.
(speaking foreign language)
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] What is it, my breath?
- [Tom] The Certs encounter.
♪ Young love, first love. ♪
- [Joel] Wow, wow, woo.
- Anne, where are you going?
- I'm just going to
sit down in the office.
- Alright.
But how can Anne help?
She doesn't know anything.
- [Joel] Obviously.
- We don't know for sure
that she can, but Sarah,
we've got to try something.
Obviously she has
some kind of contact
with these things
- obviously.
- whether she knows it or not.
I thought perhaps with you
controlling her thinking
we might be able
to learn something
about what we're dealing with.
- I suppose we could try.
- [Joel] Maybe that's what
those eyes want is contacts.
- The monitor on the top, Carl,
it's going down all the time.
- It's 45 below.
- It's still dropping, it's
the cloud location isn't it?
- There is a cloud
out there, yes.
- Wait a minute, say
it's cold they need.
They live in cold.
Remember the phone
wires at the hut?
- [Joel] They're cold.
And Brett complained of being
hot after being infected.
- [Joel] He was cold.
- And Hans too, he
complained of it.
- [Joel] Because they were cold.
- He arrived a few moments ago.
- [Joel] He's cold.
- He said he changed his
mind about trying to escape.
- Where is he?
- Out in the corridor.
- He's cold.
- [Tom] Hans is on the fritz.
- Where's Hans?
- [Joel] He had a cold.
- He went inside a minute ago.
- He came in here.
- Alan!
- [Tom] Get your hand off me.
- [Crow] Hey, one at
a time, one at a time.
- [Joel] No leap frog, come on.
Quit rough-housing.
- [Crow] Everyone
will get a chance.
- Wait, wait my dear, please.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Take it back,
take it back what you said
about my eye.
- [Crow] Uncle, uncle.
Tickle machine, tickle machine.
- [Tom] Hans across
the letter opener.
- [Crow] He's washed
his Hans of that.
- [Tom] Wait'll I
get my Hans on you.
- He'll be alright, I think.
- Wilde, you better
take care of him.
- [Crow] I think
you already did.
- [Joel] Are you hurting?
- [Tom] Did you bring any fish?
- [Crow] He'll get over it.
- How thick are these walls?
- I don't know, two,
three feet maybe.
- Fireproof?
- Well yes, they're
reinforced concrete
against the avalanches.
- Good, Hugo, get on the radio.
United Nations in Bern, I
wanna talk to Colonel Stillman.
- [Joel] Yowza.
Now that Anne can't
help us anymore,
there's only one thing left.
- What's that?
- What I said before.
Every time we've come
up against these things,
there's been this intense cold.
Remember you said that
Brett looked like he'd been
in the deep freeze.
Heat, that's what
we've gotta use.
I'm gonna ask for
a bombing raid.
- You said that was impossible.
- Fire bombs, that's our answer.
- [Hugo] Through to
Bern, Mr. Brooks.
- [Tom] Fire bombs,
you just hired them.
- I want all the jars
and bottles you've got.
- [Joel] Get me six bags of
onions and a giant eye chart.
(warbling)
It's getting creepy.
(whistling)
Ah, it's cold.
(coughing)
- [Tom] Give him
a giant scissors,
maybe he'll put himself out.
- [Crow] Well all eyes are
on the observatory now.
- [Tom] Is there a
sequel to this movie?
- [Crow] Yes, the Eye-ger
Sanction. (chuckling)
(groaning)
- [Tom] Starring Burl Eyes.
(chuckling)
- [Joel] I mean,
I don't get this.
What's a giant eye
gonna do to you anyway,
like pick you up and
wink you to death?
It's just not gonna
happen, it's not practical.
- [Tom] Well, we're all
eye witnesses, though.
- [Crow] Mine eyes
have seen the gory.
- [Joel] Ooh, you did it again.
- Ooh.
- Kind of a, ah well.
- [Tom] Pretty high brow.
(chuckling)
- I think I'd put
more in that one.
- [Joel] That's
the way I like 'em.
- [Tom] A very dry fire bomb.
- Tight so the
petrol won't leak.
- [Joel] Yep got it.
- [Tom] shaken, not stirred.
- Could I have your
attention, please?
I don't want anyone
to leave this corridor
unless I say so, understood.
- [Joel] What if we have to go?
- As many of these
ready as you can and
- [Tom] Hold 'em.
- Be careful of 'em,
they're dangerous.
And I can tell ya that
help's on its way.
- [Joel] I can't
guarantee you'll survive.
- [Crow] Well, they
seemed to buy it.
- Alan.
- Yeah?
- How we gonna use
these bombs of yours?
- You light the
rags and throw 'em
at those things in the cloud.
- [Tom] Then you run,
is that so complicated?
- Look at this.
♪ Eye, eye, eye, eye ♪
- [Crow] Wow, now
I know how it feels
to be in a microscope.
- Cute little
things, aren't they?
- Yeah, I'm gonna throw
a bomb at that one.
You watch on the screen--
- [Tom] One of your
movies, Forrest?
- Would you all go to the far
end of the corridor, please?
Except you, you come with me.
- [Joel] Huh, why me?
- I want you to slam
this door behind me,
wait for me to knock
to come back in.
If I don't knock,
don't open it right?
- [Crow] Right, okay,
so if you knock, uh,
I open it, alright, okay.
Now if you don't knock, wait,
lemme get a piece of paper.
Darn.
(spacey buzzing)
♪ Shave and a haircut ♪
- [Crow] Who is it?
Oh, it's you.
- Get me a couple
more of those bottles.
- I saw it on the screen.
- Those things can really move.
You really got to
get a direct hit
and surround 'em with so much
flame they can't get out.
- Let me try.
- [Tom] Okay, but it's
not that fun, go ahead.
- [Crow] Remember
the secret knock.
- [Joel] What knock?
- [Tom] Wait, they are big.
- [Joel] Uh oh.
- Alan, there's one on the roof.
- [Tom] He's got a
new lash on life.
- [Crow] But he
didn't knock yet.
Okay, same knock deal?
Rats, I missed.
Saved him in the
blink of an eye.
- [Tom] Nice stunt, though.
- [Joel] Whoa, rugged.
- Thanks.
You alright?
- [Joel] I feel so dirty.
- Thanks, Alan.
Now what?
- I don't know.
Can't go out that door
again, that's for sure.
It's the only way in or out
of this observatory,
I've checked.
- [Crow] Maybe we should panic.
- [Joel] Maybe we should
go to a commercial?
- [Tom] We could take a
short break for the tedium.
- [Joel] Did you
guys get enough eyes?
Have you seen enough
horrible eyes yet?
- Yeah?
- [Crow] Hm, yeah,
my eyes are burning.
(upbeat music)
- What are they doing now?
- Can't tell anymore,
they blocked out the
cameras, you see?
- [Tom] It's all teared up.
♪ Here I come to save the day ♪
- Jolly Roger to observatory.
Jolly Roger to observatory.
Receiving you loud and clear.
ETA in five minutes.
- [Tom] No need to come
to the party anymore.
All the cool people are dead.
- He says ETA in
about five minutes.
- Good, tell him to
make straight run
over the observatory
and to drop his
bombs on the roof.
I hope he knows what he's doing.
- [Joel] I hope you
know what you're doing.
- [Tom] How's she doing?
- No change?
- [Crow] No change,
couple of bills,
went through her
purse, found my comb.
That eye is lashing
out at society.
(voice chattering on radio)
- [Tom] Getting quite a
brow beating on these puns.
- Hello, Jolly Roger.
Drop first on the observatory
and cloud, understand?
Bomb the cloud as well, over.
- [Pilot] Listen, observatory,
sounds crazy to me,
bombing a cloud, over.
- Do as you're told, over.
- [Pilot] Yes sir, out.
- [Tom] Whoever cast this
movie had an eye for talent.
- [Joel] Okay,
that's it, stop it.
- [Crow] Joel's getting
really eye-rate.
(laughing)
- Thanks you guys.
Thanks for everything.
- [Tom] I can see the problem.
- We shall know soon enough.
- [Joel] I spy
with my little eye.
- [Tom] You hypocrite.
- [Joel] Something that
sounds like a gigantic eye.
Long, longer, longest.
Beautiful eyelashes that grab
people and strangle them.
- [Tom] That is one
eye-full tower, ho.
- You're hurtin' it.
- It hurts, doesn't it?
Just keep in mind,
you programmed me.
- [Joel] It's the last time
I give you free will though.
That's it, after today.
- Whoa!
- [Crow] That'll
make the mascara run.
(plane roaring)
- [Pilot] I'll try a
high level attack first.
Here we go.
- [Crow] I feel
the need, the need
- [Crow And Tom] For speed.
- [Crow] Or an antidepressant.
- [Joel] Torah, torah, torah.
- [Pilot] Ready, bomb's away.
- [Tom] I'm on the ship Arizona.
- [Crow] Where's Major Carr?
- [Joel] So that's what it
sounds like when eyes cry.
- [Crow] And we're
an eye witness.
- [Tom] I beat you to
that one. (chuckling)
- [Crow] I guess I'm
kinda eye witless.
Eye blame myself.
- [Joel] Come on, be
quiet, there's a lot
of destruction we should
be paying attention to.
- [Tom] Eye, eye, eye.
(bomb exploding)
- [Joel] I'd like
to shake tentacles
with any eye that could
last through that,
that's for sure.
- [Tom] It looks like a bunch
of overcooked fried eggs.
- [Crow] I bet it smells good.
- [Joel] I bet they don't
go out for breakfast
after this battle,
that's for sure.
(bomb dropping)
(intense music)
- [Crow] Kingsford eyeballs,
edges light quick, burn clean.
(Joel chuckling)
- [Tom] I like mine
mesquite grilled.
He tips his wings as he
flies off into the sunset.
(intense music)
- [Crow] Ookey.
- [Joel] Ucky.
(Joel squeaking)
There's that mountain.
- Oh, Wilde, tell the
villagers they can
go down the mountain
anytime they'd like.
- [Joel] And tell the
villagers to wear boots.
- How 'bout a
breath of fresh air?
- [Tom] I don't think
outside is the place
to get some fresh air right now.
- Well Sarah, doesn't
look as though you'll have
to worry about her any longer.
- No it doesn't.
- Cigarette?
- [Tom] Yes it is.
- Well Alan, for the
first time in weeks,
the Trullenberg is
free from clouds.
- Yes, and let's hope
it stays that way.
♪ I can see clearly
now the rain is gone ♪
♪ I can see all
obstacles in my way ♪
(triumphant music)
(steam hissing)
(doors clanking and whirring)
- Alright, that's the end
of the movie everybody.
And you know what that means.
- [Robots] Yay!
- Ram chips and dip.
- And afterwards, a
borium power flush.
- [Robots] Boo.
- I'm just kidding.
- [Robots] Yay!
- Okay, now you
know how it works.
No, no, just wait your
turn, you'll get a ram chip.
Okay, Crow, you go first.
Now tell me a good thing about
the movie and the bad thing
and you'll get your ram chip.
Good thing?
- The good thing was
that it wasn't longer.
- Okay and the bad thing?
- It was this long.
- Okay, there's your
ram chip, pally, okay.
- Yay!
- Open up, there you go.
- All right, okay.
- Can I have a ram chip now?
- No, no, wait up on
your ram chip, Gypsy.
- Okay, Tom Servo.
- Alright, okay, let's
see, the good thing was
that we didn't have
to watch them clean up
the vitreous humor all over
from the eyes exploding.
Okay, imagine, you sign up
that day for Kelly Temps,
Trullenberg office of course,
they give you a leaky
bucket and a turkey baster,
send you up the mountain,
now you're on clean up crew.
- And the bad thing?
- Well the bad thing
was, the movie?
It was ambitious,
but it lacked vision.
(chuckling)
- Well, hindsight, is 20/20.
- Terrific, okay.
Well here's your ram chip, pal.
- Thank you.
- Okay, okay, it's time
for your ram chip, Gypsy.
All you gotta do is
answer the questions
and you get the ram chips, okay?
- Fine.
- Alright.
Tell me a good thing
about the movie.
- K, can I have a ram chip now?
- Well tell me a bad thing
about the movie, Gypsy.
Oh, you don't know, okay, okay.
Just answer this one question
and I'll give you a ram chip.
What's two plus two?
- Richard Baysar?
- Oh, good one, okay,
there you go alright, yeah.
Okay, well, that's the end
of the experiment, you guys.
Hope you're happy.
- Oh, I'm happy, are you happy?
- Oh, I'm happy,
here, file this.
(cackling)
well, we'll see you next time,
Joely Poley pudding and pie.
(trumpeting orchestral music)